Guide to the Papers of George L. Mosse (1918-1999), 1780-2001 AR 25137 / MF 671
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series III: Correspondence, 1919-2001; 22 linear feet
  - Subseries 6: Students, 1961-1991; 1 linear foot
    - B) Individuals
      - Chandler, Jeff, 1984-1986 (Box 51, Folder 36)
      - Chertok, David, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 37)
      - Chin-Duke, Josephine, 1982-1983 (Box 51, Folder 38)
      - Cinelli, E.M., 1975 (Box 51, Folder 39)
      - Cobb, James, 1975-1977 (Box 51, Folder 40)
      - Cole, Jeffrey, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 41)
      - Cooperman, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 42)
      - Cross, Casey, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 43)
      - Czerkas, Andreas, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 44)
      - Davis, Russell, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 45)
      - Dreben, Michael, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 46)
      - Dubbs, Thomas, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 47)
      - Edelstein, Ruth M., 1975 (Box 51, Folder 48)
      - Eils, Robert Charles, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 49)
      - Engelstein, Larry, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 50)
      - Ettenheim, Tim, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 51)
      - Even-Shoshan, Moshe, 1974-1978 (Box 51, Folder 52)
      - Feldman, Ellen, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 53)
      - Feldmen, Ron, undated (Box 51, Folder 54)
      - Ferguson, Mark, 1979-1982 (Box 51, Folder 55)
      - Finkelstein, Amnon G., 1985 (Box 51, Folder 56)
      - Fischer, Larry, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 57)
      - Fitzgerald, Maureen, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 58)
      - Friedman, Bernard, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 59)
      - Gargan, Edward Jr., 1973-1975 (Box 51, Folder 60)
      - Garnett, Clarke, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 61)
      - Gatzke, Hans, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 62)
      - Gerber, Marcus, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 63)
      - Gereau, Sandra, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 64)
      - Glauberman, Naomi, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 65)
      - Glick, Nancy R., 1986-1987 (Box 51, Folder 66)
      - Golden, Ken, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 67)
      - Goldman, Eddie, 1972-1978 (Box 51, Folder 68)
      - Goodman, Andrew, 1977-1980 (Box 51, Folder 69)
      - Goodman, Harold, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 70)
      - Goodman, Jim, 1970-1972 (Box 51, Folder 71)
      - Gordon, Adam Henry, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 72)
      - Gordon, Bonnie, 1976-1979 (Box 51, Folder 73)
      - Goren, Avi, 1974-1976 (Box 51, Folder 74)
      - Greene, Richard, 1973-1976 (Box 51, Folder 75)
      - Greenstein, Stephen Joel, 1967-1970 (Box 51, Folder 76)
      - Greenstein, Steve, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 77)
      - Grendler, Paul, 1977-1986 (Box 51, Folder 78)
      - Grobman, Alex, 1970-1977 (Box 51, Folder 79)
      - Grunstein, Arturo, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 80)
      - Haley, John, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 81)
      - Haller, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 82)
      - Hansen, Linda, 1968-1970 (Box 51, Folder 83)
      - Harris, David, 1972-1973 (Box 51, Folder 84)
      - Harris, Zachary, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 85)
      - Haskin, Linda, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 86)
      - Hatheway, Joseph, 1980-1986 (Box 51, Folder 87)
      - Heneghan, Craig D., 1978 (Box 51, Folder 88)
      - Hertz, Deborah, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 89)
      - Heyd, Michael, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 90)
      - Hilgendorf, Mark, 1973-1974 (Box 51, Folder 91)
      - Hirschberg, Michael, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 92)
      - Hirshman, Debra, 1975-1976 (Box 51, Folder 93)
      - Holden, David H., 1971 (Box 51, Folder 94)
      - Holter, Howard R., 1975 (Box 51, Folder 95)
      - Horn, Colin, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 96)
      - Huyge, Louisa, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 97)
      - Hutcheson, Michael, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 98)
      - Itzkowitz, Joel, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 99)
      - Jaliman, Michael, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 100)
      - Johnson, David, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 101)
      - Jubelirer, Eliot, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 102)
      - Kahn, William, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 103)
      - Kale, Steven, 1983-1986 (Box 51, Folder 104)
      - Kalmonoff, Wendy, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 105)
      - Kamal, Sami, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 106)
      - Kaminsky, Mark, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 107)
      - Kaplow, Jeffry, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 108)
      - Karmel, Jonathon, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 109)
      - Kaufman, Allan, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 110)
      - Kaufman, Lanny, 1970-1972 (Box 51, Folder 111)
      - Kaye, Joel, 1970-1979 (Box 51, Folder 112)
      - Kelly, Art, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 113)
      - Kelman, Levi Yehudah, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 114)
      - Kirschbaum, Aaron, 1968-1971 (Box 51, Folder 115)
      - Kokott, Robert, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 116)
      - Kolstad, Michael, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 117)
      - Koransky, Henry, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 118)
      - Kraemer, Seymour, 1971-1973 (Box 51, Folder 119)
      - Kritzman, Lawrence, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 120)
      - Kurth, David, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 121)
      - Lagana, Marc, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 122)
      - Lake, Sheila E., 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 123)
      - Lakin, Michael, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 124)
      - Lam, Doron, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 125)
      - Lampert, Steve, 1977-1979 (Box 51, Folder 126)
      - Lavine, Joseph, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 127)
      - Lennox, Frank, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 128)
      - Lerman, David, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 129)
      - Levin, Steven M., 1973 (Box 51, Folder 130)
      - Levine, Arnold, 1972-1974 (Box 51, Folder 131)
      - Levine, Michael G., 1970-1974 (Box 51, Folder 132)
      - Levinson, Larry, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 133)
      - Liss, Harvey, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 134)
      - Loewenberg, Peter, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 135)
      - Lyons, Douglas, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 136)
      - Maid, Barry, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 137)
      - Mandel, Mark, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 138)
      - Mann, Paul W., 1972 (Box 51, Folder 139)
      - Manning, Paul E., 1982 (Box 51, Folder 140)
      - Marcus, Alfred, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 141)
      - Marks, Elaine, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 142)
      - Marks, Harry, 1972-1974 (Box 51, Folder 143)
      - Martinson, Andre, 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 144)
      - Maslan, Susan, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 145)
      - Matlofsky, Gerald, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 146)
      - McDonald, Michael, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 147)
      - McCann, Dennis, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 148)
      - McCann, Kaaren, 1967-1980 (Box 51, Folder 149)
      - McGee, Eugene, 1962-1970 (Box 51, Folder 150)
      - McGhee, Patricia, 1970-1973 (Box 51, Folder 151)
      - Melton, David, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 152)
      - Mentzer, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 153)
      - Merwick, Donna, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 154)
      - Meshbesher, Steven, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 155)
      - Michaelis, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 156)
      - Miller, Mark, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 157)
      - Miller, Nancy, 1970-1974 (Box 51, Folder 158)
      - Miller, Timothy, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 159)
      - Morris, Errol M., 1970 (Box 51, Folder 160)
      - Morse, Stephan Wayne, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 161)
      - Natanson, Charles, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 162)
      - Needleman, Arthur, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 163)
      - Neren, Steven H., 1977 (Box 51, Folder 164)
      - Netzer, William, 1966-1969, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 165)
      - Nilles, Jill, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 166)
      - Nohel, Richard, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 167)
      - Oberlander, Joab Z., 1971 (Box 51, Folder 168)
      - Olson, Anne Michelle, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 169)
      - Olson, Roger D., 1973 (Box 51, Folder 170)
      - Patner, Andrew, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 171)
      - Pearson, Thomas C., 1980-1981 (Box 51, Folder 172)
      - Perry, Debra, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 173)
      - Peters, Walter Hugh, 1967-1972 (Box 51, Folder 174)
      - Peterson, Brian L., 1971-1977 (Box 51, Folder 175)
      - Peterson, Marcia, 1972-1975 (Box 51, Folder 176)
      - Peterson, Ross, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 177)
      - Phillips, Todd, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 178)
      - Pollack, David, 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 179)
      - Pollack, Raphael, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 180)
      - Poppell, Stephen, 1974-1975 (Box 51, Folder 181)
      - Prombaum, Saul, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 182)
      - Raben, Harvey, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 183)
      - Ranard, Andrew B., 1981 (Box 51, Folder 184)
      - Reed, Robert, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 185)
      - Reeder, Linda, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 186)
      - Rodenstein, Laurence, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 187)
      - Rolling, John D., 1979 (Box 51, Folder 188)
      - Rood, Vernon Paul, 1978-1982 (Box 51, Folder 189)
      - Rosen, David, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 190)
      - Rothstein, Andrew, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 191)
      - Rubenstein, Robert, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 192)
      - Ruby, Walter, 1971-1973 (Box 51, Folder 193)
      - Ryan, Michael T., 1975 (Box 51, Folder 194)
      - Samuelson, Arthur H., 1974-1975 (Box 51, Folder 195)
      - Sandford, Gregory, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 196)
      - Schafritz, Robert, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 197)
      - Schaller, John, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 198)
      - Schalow, Thomas, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 199)
      - Scheerer, Katherine, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 200)
      - Schesch, Adam, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 201)
      - Schilling, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 202)
      - Schipper, Henry, 1974-1975 (Box 51, Folder 203)
      - Schlanger, Harley, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 204)
      - Schultz, Barnett, 1980-1983 (Box 51, Folder 205)
      - Schwartz, Daniel, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 206)
      - Schwartz, Robert A., 1973-1985 (Box 51, Folder 207)
      - Seager, Richard Hughes, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 208)
      - Segal, Peter, 1979-1980 (Box 51, Folder 209)
      - Seidemann, Daniel, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 210)
      - Seldin, Beth, 1984-1985 (Box 51, Folder 211)
      - Shalom, Nina, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 212)
      - Shinder, Jack, 1977-1979 (Box 51, Folder 213)
      - Shulman, Arthur, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 214)
      - Siegel, Paul, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 215)
      - Slate, William, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 216)
      - Soliday, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 217)
      - Soman, Jean Powers, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 218)
      - Stacy, William, 1978-1979 (Box 51, Folder 219)
      - Star, Philip, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 220)
      - Stein, Alan, 1967-1968 (Box 51, Folder 221)
      - Stein, Jeffrey, 1966-1968 (Box 51, Folder 222)
      - Stein, Steven, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 223)
      - Steinberg, Mark, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 224)
      - Steinzor, Rena, 1972-1973 (Box 51, Folder 225)
      - Stockinger, Jacob, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 226)
      - Stovall, Tyler, 1978-1983 (Box 51, Folder 227)
      - Stroik, Lawrence Michael, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 228)
      - Stuart, Julia, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 229)
      - Stulberg, Neal, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 230)
      - Tankel, Joshua, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 231)
      - Teplinsky, Steven J., 1985 (Box 51, Folder 232)
      - Tishman, Steven M., 1981 (Box 51, Folder 233)
      - Tomich, Dale, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 234)
      - Tonkens, Nancy, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 235)
      - Torda, Phyllis, 1976-1977 (Box 51, Folder 236)
      - Vetener, Steve, 1973-1974 (Box 51, Folder 237)
      - Vickerman, Michael, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 238)
      - Wald, James John, 1977-1978 (Box 51, Folder 239)
      - Warren, Mitchell, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 240)
      - Web, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 241)
      - Wegner, Robert, 1972-1974 (Box 51, Folder 242)
      - Weiner, Steven, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 243)
      - Weinig, Judith, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 244)
      - Weiss, Anne W., 1978 (Box 51, Folder 245)
      - Werner, Stephen, 1971-1974 (Box 51, Folder 246)
      - Wertheimer, Ralph, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 247)
      - Weston, Timothy, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 248)
      - Wetzler, Peter, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 249)
      - Wienberg, Paul, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 250)
      - Willis, Kirk, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 251)
      - Winograd, Richard, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 252)
      - Winston, Colin, 1978-1982 (Box 51, Folder 253)
      - Winston, Michael, 1971-1986 (Box 51, Folder 254)
      - Wiseman, John M., 1973 (Box 51, Folder 255)
      - Wood, Robert C., 1988-1991 (Box 51, Folder 256)
      - Wuerth, Dieter, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 257)
      - Zabin, Jerry M., 1976 (Box 51, Folder 258)
      - Zola, John, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 259)
- Series IV: Photos and Pictorial Material, undated, 1930s-1998; 1 linear foot
  The photographic materials in the George L. Mosse collection include: black and white and color photographs,negatives,film, and slides. The images span Mosse's lifetime and consist mainly of photographs of Mosse, his friends and colleagues, his home in Madison, Wisconsin, and the various international locations to which he traveled in pursuit of his research interests as well as on personal holidays. There are some photographs representing George L. Mosse's immediate family as well as his early life in Germany. Photographs from the 1990s show Mosse's return trip to Germany to visit Mosse family homes and estates which had been inaccessible until the fall of Communism. There are some undated and unidentified photographs.
  Several framed pictures have also been placed in this series. The frames were removed for preservation purposes.
  - A) Film
    - 16mm Film, Labeled Salem, Hermannsberg, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Undeveloped Roll, Exposed Kodak Film, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - B) Photos
    - a) George L. Mosse and Friends
      - Anson Rabinbach and Judy - North Hampton, 1970s? (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - George L Mosse, 1930s-1990s (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - George L. Mosse, 1930s-1990s (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - George L. Mosse, 1930s-1990s (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - George L. Mosse - Portraits, undated (Box OSL41, Folder 11)
      - George L. Mosse Receiving Leo Baeck Medal at the 4th Annual Leo Baeck Gala Dinner, November 18, 1998 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - George L. Mosse with Identified People, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - George L. Mosse with Unidentified People, span 1950s-1990s (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Family, undated (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Felicia Lachmann-Mosse, undated (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Identified friends and colleagues, undated (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Joy Mosse, undated (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - MosseFest, 1998 (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Pets, undated (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Portraits, undated (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Steve Aschheim - Jericho, Israel, 1980s (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Unidentified Family, undated (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified People, span 1950s-1990s (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - b) Sites
      - 36 Glenway, Madison WI, span 1956-1990s (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - The Alps, 1930s- (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - Australia, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 22)
      - Australia and Tahiti, 1970s? (Box 52, Folder 23)
      - Belgium, undated (Box 52, Folder 24)
      - Chamonix/ Mt. Blanc, 1930s? (Box 52, Folder 25)
      - Egypt, undated (Box 52, Folder 26)
      - Egypt - On the Nile River, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 27)
      - England, undated (Box 52, Folder 28)
      - Frank Lloyd Wright Farm, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 29)
      - Germany, undated (Box 52, Folder 30)
      - Germany, spring 1989 (Box 52, Folder 31)
      - Germany, 1996, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 32)
      - Germany - Berlin, 1990s? (Box 52, Folder 33)
      - Germany - Schenkendorf, undated, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 34)
      - Guadalupe, undated (Box 52, Folder 35)
      - Guatemala, 1963? 1964? (Box 52, Folder 36)
      - Haiti, undated (Box 52, Folder 37)
      - Israel, span 1970s-1990s? (Box 52, Folder 38)
      - Israel - Lake Galillee - Summer Kibbutz, 1970s? (Box 52, Folder 39)
      - Israel - Mosse and Andy, 1976? 1978? (Box 52, Folder 40)
      - Italy, 1954? (Box 52, Folder 41)
      - Italy, December 1996 (Box 52, Folder 42)
      - Italy - Pisa, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 43)
      - Italy - Tomb of Mussolini, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 44)
      - Italy - Venice, undated (Box 52, Folder 45)
      - Mexico, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 46)
      - Mosse Family Homes, undated (Box 52, Folder 47)
      - New York City, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 48)
      - Nuestra Señora del Pilar - Commemoration?, undated (Box 52, Folder 49)
      - Postcards, undated (Box 52, Folder 50)
      - Prague, Other European Cities, 1968? (Box 52, Folder 51)
      - South Africa, undated (Box 52, Folder 52)
      - Unidentified Cities and Buildings, undated (Box 52, Folder 53)
      - Unidentified Homes, undated (Box 52, Folder 54)
  - C) Pictures
    - Cartoon, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 55)
    - Feldherrnhalle in München - Picture, undated (Box 62, Folder 56)
    - Framed Newspaper Article, undated (Box 62, Folder 57)
    - Zweibürgenblick - Picture, undated (Box 62, Folder 58)
    - Photo - Fountain, undated (Box 62, Folder 59)
  - D) Negatives
    - 36 Glenway, Madison, WI, 1960s? (Box 52, Folder 60)
    - Italy, 1950s (Box 52, Folder 61)
    - George L. Mosse, Unidentified Man and Woman - Roll, undated (Box 52, Folder 62)
    - Mosse, Unidentified People, 1950s? (Box 52, Folder 63)
    - Pets, undated (Box 52, Folder 64)
    - Unidentified Locations, undated (Box 52, Folder 65)
    - Unidentified Locations and People, undated (Box 52, Folder 66)
  - E) Slides
    - Germany, Italy, Israel, Southwest, undated (Box 52, Folder 67)
    - 36 Glenway, Madison, WI, undated (Box 52, Folder 68)
    - 36 Glenway, Madison, WI - George L. Mosse with Pets, 1990s? (Box 52, Folder 69)
    - Europe?, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 70)
    - France or Italy?, undated (Box 52, Folder 71)
    - Guatemala, 1963 or 1964? (Box 52, Folder 72)
    - Italy?, Europe, undated (Box 52, Folder 73)
    - Schenkendorf, 1990s (Box 52, Folder 74)
    - Travel Photo, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 75)
    - Travel Slides? England?, July 1957 (Box 52, Folder 76)
    - Travel slides - Europe, Other Locations, undated (Box 52, Folder 77)
    - University of Wisconsin - Madison Prank on Mosse, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 78)
    - Various Locations - George L. Mosse with Friends, undated (Box 52, Folder 79)
- Series V: Audiovisual Material, 1955-1961; 1 linear foot
  By format, then by order in film series.
  This series is comprised of a series of films that George L. Mosse worked on for Coronet Instructional films. George L. Mosse was the historical consultant for the films, which were designed to give an overview of a historical period for classroom use. The films cover European history as well as the exploration of the Americas, and cover topics from the time of the Holy Roman Empire through the Glorious Revolution in England. The films are in the form of film reels as well as videocassettes. Videocassettes contain several films, whereas reels have one film each. Drafts of three of the films may be found in Series II, Subseries 1.
  - A) Film Reels
    - Age of Discovery: English, French and Dutch Explorations - Film Reel, 1956? (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - English History: Absolutism and Civil War - Film Reel, 1958? (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - English History: Restoration and Glorious Revolution - Film Reel, 1958? (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - B) Videocassettes
    - The Holy Roman Empire; Medieval Times: the Role of the Church; Charlemagne and His Empire; The Refomation - Videocassettes, 1955, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Age of Discovery; English, French and Dutch Explorations; English History: Absolutism and Civil War; English History: Restoration and Glorious Revolution - Videocassettes, 1956, 1958 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - C) Larger Film Reels
    - Charlemagne and his Empire - Larger Film Reel, 1961? (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - The Holy Roman Empire - Larger Film Reel, 1961? (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Medieval Times: the Role of the Church - Larger Film Reel, 1955? (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - The Reformation - Larger Film Reel, 1961? (Box 53, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Objects, 1986-1995; 1.5 linear feet
  This series is made up of personal objects which belonged to George L. Mosse. The majority of objects contained here are awards or awards given to him by various organizations, such as Hadassah and the American Historical Association, among others. Other objects are of a more personal nature, such as eyeglasses, a travel bag, and a watch.
  - American Historical Association Award for Scholarly Distinction - Plaque, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Frontiers Lifetime Achievement Award, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Hadassah Acknowledgement - Plaque, undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Hadassah Myrtle Wreath Humanitarian Award - Plaque, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Hilldale Award - Plaque, 1988-1989 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Human Rights Campaign Pin, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Inscribed Leather Case, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Kenneth B. Smilen Literary Award - Plaque, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Picture Easel, undated (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Star of David - Statue, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Eyeglasses, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - KLM Travel Bag, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Watch, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Books, 1878-1996; 3 linear feet
  By language, then alphabetical.
  Series VII: Books is comprised of books in the possession of George L. Mosse. The vast majority of books are his or translations of his works. Drafts of some of this works may be found in Series II: Writings, Subseries 1: Writings, and correspondence concerening them is in Series III, Subseries 3: Personal. Section E contains books not written by Mosse, but included in his collection. Several of these refer to his family's possessions, including the Kunstsammlung Rudolf Mosse, Berlin and the Zeitungs-Annoncen Expidition Rudolf Mosse.Touching the Sky was a book given as a gift to George L. Mosse.
  - A) English
    - Calvinism: Authoritarian or Democratic?, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Culture of Western Europe, 1961, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Europe in Review, 1957, 1964, 1972 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Image of Man, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Nationalism: the Nature and Evolution of an Idea, 1973, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Outline and Sources for a History of Western, 1948, 1951 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Reformation, 1953, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Source Readings - Western Civilization in Modern Times, 1945 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Struggle for Sovereignty in England, 1950, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Survivors, Victims, and Perpetrators, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Toward the Final Solution, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - B) German
    - Ein Volk - Ein Reich - Ein Führer, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Entartete Kunst, 1991, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Nationalisierung der Massen, 1975, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Nationalismus und Sexualität, 1985 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Zeitmitschrift - 1937. Europa vor dem 2. Weltkrieg, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - C) Italian
    - Dialogo Ebraico-Tedesco, 1985, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Guerre Mondiale Dalla Tragedia al Mito Dei Caduti, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Intervista sul Nazismo, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Nazionalizzazione delle Masse, 1974, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Origini Culturali del Terzo Reich, 1964, 1968, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Origini Culturali del Terzo Reich, 1964, 1968, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Razzismo in Europa, 1978, 1985 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Razzismo in Europa, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Sessualita' e Nazionalismo, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - D) Other
    - Nationalization of the Masses- Japanese Version, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - E) Not by George L. Mosse
    - 50 Jahre F.E. Weidenmüller Antonsthal, 1867-1917 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Kunstsammlung Rudolf Mosse, Berlin, undated, 1878 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Nazi-Kitsch, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - 75 Jahre Berliner Börsen-Zeitung, 1930? (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Special Life Edition - Israel's Swift History, 1967 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Touching the Sky by Denise Low and George Kren, 1994 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Zeitungs Katalog Annoncen-Expedition Rudolf Mosse, 1927 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Zeitungs Katalog Annoncen-Expedition Rudolf Mosse, 1933 (Box 58, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Offprints, 1780-1998; 8 linear feet